ASWINI SWAIN

8249240984 · aswiniswain121@gmail.com · <u>www.linkedin.com/in/aswini-swain-28a417269</u> . Hyderabad, India.

ABOUT ME

Software Engineer with 1 year of experience in full-stack and WWMS development. Led significant upgrades for Singapore Power's RRU application and also led a key role in the CEM Macau Project. I developed a web application using HTML, CSS, and JAVASCRIPT and created an API for that system using the Swagger tool. Additionally, I modified Oracle 19C triggers and stored procedures, improving application functionality and ensuring smooth system operation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS	
------------------	--

Java	HTML	SQL
J2EE	CSS	MYSQL
Hibernate	JavaScript	Oracle
SpringBoot	ReactJs	

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Inovaantage Pvt. Ltd Metering Data Management Project, Singapore Power, Singapore,

October 2023 - Present

On-site collaboration with Singapore Power, directly managing upgrades for the WWMS application; streamlined processes that facilitated the successful implementation of some new features requested by end-users.

Accomplishments:

- Collaborated in Optimizing Oracle database triggers and stored procedures to ensure data integrity and efficient system optimizations.
- Collaborated in deployment of database and application changes in QA and production environments.
- Conducted database load testing and performance testing, ensuring robust data handling during high-traffic scenarios.
- Used HP-ALM for defect tracking, RCA documentation, and test management during development and production cycles.

Electrical Meter Replacement Project, SingaporePower, Singapore

October 2023 - Present

Accomplishments:

- Digitization of investigation and report (YQ and YK) notifications work processes.
- Enhancement of 'Skip mandatory' functionality to bulk meter installation workflow (EMI-YQ and EMI-YU).
- Also Used HP-ALM for defect tracking, RCA documentation, and test management during development and production cycles.

Collaborated in deployment of database and application changes in QA and production environments

Software Developer, Inovaantage Pvt. Ltd

CEM (Companhia de Electricidade de Macau) Project, Macau:

January 2024- Aug 2024

Accomplishments:

- Developed and maintained responsive web applications using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, ensuring cross-browser compatibility.
- ·Leveraged frameworks like Bootstrap for dynamic, responsive user interfaces.
- ·Collaborated with UX/UI designers and backend developers to integrate RESTful APIs and translate design mock-ups into functional web pages.

EDUCATION

Trident Academy Of Technology, Biju patnaik University Of Technology, Odisha

MCA, 2022, Bhubaneswar, India

Utkal University, Odisha

Bachelor of Science (Honours)

Maharshi College Of Natural Law, Odisha

Intermediate, Bhubaneswar